

CONTACT

- **Q** 0172 / 60 811 49
- abdulsalam-emesh.me
- abdulsalam.emesh.work@gmail.com

SKILLS

- PHP
- Bitbucket
- Laravel
- Jira
- OOP
- TDD
- PHPStorm
- MySQL
- JavaScript
- Datagrip
- Vue
- MVC
- Alpine.js
- NPM
- Livewire
- Yarn
- CSS
- Webpack
- Tailwind CSS
- Vite
- Bootstrap
- SSH
- Git
- FTP/SFTP
- Github
- JSON

ABDULSALAM EMESH

Software Developer

Hi, I have been on this earth for about **31 years** and started my journey in **Aleppo, Syria**. I have been living in my second home **Xanten, Germany** for **7 years** now.

I am one of the lucky ones who turned their **hobby** and **passion** into a **profession**. I love **structure** and **order**, and I also stand for **quality**.

I also like to work in a **team**, where I **learn** a lot and quickly. As the german saying goes: "Alone you are strong, together unbeatable".

EDUCATION

Training as IT Specialist For Application Development 2018 - 2021 Business Technical College / Duisburg-Mitte

C1 language course

2017 - 2018 HHU / Düsseldorf

Language courses up to B2 level

2016 - 2017 VHS / Wesel

Business study

2013 - 2015 Cairo Uni / Cairo

Business study

2011 - 2013 Alepp Uni / Aleppo

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

LASE PECO SYSTEMTECHNIK GMBH

From 2021-09-01 until today

My area of responsibility is: Test driven development (TDD), planing, implementation and maintenance of two (Laravel and Vue) cloud based platforms as well as connecting and implementing the API of various types of new and old laser-counting devices to the clouds. Configuration and installation of a local server on a local PC for a laser scanner device and connecting it to the Internet. Aggregating and saving the data of the laser scanner devices and generating statistics from the data and displaying it in various implementations in the clouds (Excel, diagrams, pivot tables)



LANGUAGES

- German B2
- English B2
- Arabic Mother language

HOBBIES

- Cycling
- Programming
- Music

OTHER

Driving license

ABDULSALAM EMESH

Software Entwickler

WORK EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

Minijob Software Developer

MEIER AG / WESEL

From 2021-09-01 until today

In addition to my main job at LASE PeCo, I support and consult my old colleague at Meier AG with the planning and organization of several projects.

Training as IT Specialist For Application Development / Junior Software Developer

MEIER AG / WESEL

From 2018 to 2021-08-31

During my apprenticeship and employment, I implemented many one-pager websites for various clients from different industries. I also worked with the team on various custom online shops and platforms using Laravel and Vue. I was responsible for planning the database structure, implementation, web user interfaces of various API interfaces (PayPal - ImmoScout24 - Coinbase - etc.).

Assistant

KOCHLÖFFEL / WESEL

From 2018 to 2019

In my first year of apprenticeship as an IT specialist for application development, I worked as a temp at Kochlöffel. And I was responsible for entering the data and admission of the goods in the warehouse. Also ordering goods and help on the cashier and be friendly service of the customers.

Assistant

CAFÉ EXTRABLATT / WESEL

From 2017 to 2018

While I was taking part in various German courses, I worked as a temp at Extrablatt. My duties included the following activities: Responsible for the registration of the acceptance and recording of the goods in the warehouse. Safety measures for the equipment in the facility. Friendly service to customers.